# WILLIAM ROTCH III

14 Pitkin Street, Burlington, VT 05401 | williamrotchIB@gmail.com | 617.953.4326 | linkedin.com/in/william-rotch-iii-809b5698/

#### FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I'm looking forward to a new career in software development after working for four years in the food service industry post college. I enjoy the creative thinking process required by coding and how components come together to form functional applications. I am an adaptive problem solver in dynamic environments with extensive experience in research, analysis, and client service both as an individual contributor and as part of a team.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

Languages
Frameworks
Database Management
Source Control
Development
Other Tools

JavaScript | HTML | CSS Node.js | React | Express | Material-UI MongoDB / Mongoose | Firebase Git | GitHub Visual Studio Trello | Postman | Axios

# Experience

OUT Maine Rockland, ME Jul 2021 – Aug 2021

Focused on supporting, educating, and empowering LGBTQ+ youth through building welcoming communities in Maine.

# **Developer – Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy**

Member of a 5-person team tasked with automating (and making mobile-responsive) the binder distribution process from initial request up to delivery. Features include preferences and prioritization, email automation for waitlist and ready-to-ship, inventory management, admin functionality, and multiple sortable fields and categories.

- Collaborated with project sponsors to design the request form and admin dashboard
- Used Agile methodologies to manage project development and stories in Trello
- Added validation and formatting functionality to request form using Validator.js
- Implemented a database for storing binder inventory, processed inventory, requests, and waitlisted requests using MongoDB, Mongoose, and Express
- Worked on CRUD functionality for database entries using MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, Axios, and Material-table
- Designed admin dashboard with multiple tabs and sortable fields using React and Material-UI
- Technology used: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node), JavaScript, Material-UI, Mongoose, Validator.js, and Trello

Starbucks Burlington, VT and Boston, MA Aug 2017 – May 2021

World's largest, multinational coffeehouse chain with over 30,000 retail stores in 83 markets.

Barista, Burlington Aug 2019 – May 2021 Barista, Boston Aug 2017 – Jul 2019

Maintained the friendly and welcoming environment that Starbucks expects and customers enjoy.

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

BA in History University of Vermont May 2017

#### Certifications

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate (480+ hours)

Burlington Code Academy, Burlington, VT (expected) Aug 2021

# SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Problem Solving
- Games Video/Tabletop/Card
- 19<sup>th</sup> Century European History
- Research, Analysis, and Writing
- Client / Customer Service
- Teamwork and Collaboration